Contact

01000501766 (Mobile) ahmedhateeem@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ahmedhatem-409abb6a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Analysis
Application Support
ITIL Certified

Languages

English

Certifications

Introduction to big data

Ccna

ITIL

Ahmed Hatem

Business intelligence specialist at Vodafone Egypt

Summary

Experienced Business Intelligence Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the telecommunications industry. Skilled in Oracle Database, Microsoft Excel, Communication, SQL,Unix,Data analytics and Data Warehousing. Strong research professional with a Bachelor of Engineering (BE) focused in Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering from Canadian international college.

Experience

Vodafone

4 years 11 months

Senior Business Intelligence Analyst July 2019 - Present (2 years 6 months) Cairo Governorate, Egypt

•Examine existing/ new business models and flows of data and discuss findings with the

business owner and other technical teams.

- •Deploy ETL jobs using IBM Inphosphere Data Stage and INFORMATICA.
- •Deploy BI reports using SAP business object "Crystal & Webi " Reports.
- Ensuring project requirements are accurately represented in solutions developed and

implemented into production environment and making the "Post Implementation Validation"

Test.

 Analyze applications repetitive problems, try to find temporary solutions and escalate to the

development team or vendor for permanent fix to minimize business impact for chronic

problems.

 Maintaining Revenue Assurance, Operational Data Store and ETL systems stability to

enhance the performance of the services.

•Ensure applications changes are followed by change management process.

•Implement system updates as per change management process to ensure proper

implementations for fixes, also new functions deployment are timely and accurately deployed

to production.

•Solve production and operational issues.

Business Intelligence Specialist July 2019 - Present (2 years 6 months) Cairo, Cairo, Egypt

Data Warehouse operations engineer February 2017 - July 2019 (2 years 6 months) Egypt

operate all the Data Warehouse models, monitoring all jobs using AJS(automated tool) And ETL tool

Smart.net
Technical Presales Engineer
April 2016 - February 2017 (11 months)
Misr al-Gadida, Cairo Governorate, Egypt

Army
Army Officer
April 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 7 months)
Worked in electronics (maintainance)

Education

Canadian international college

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Electrical, Electronics and Communications

Engineering · (2008 - 2013)